<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignment overview | Measurement/Evaluation in Educational Psychology</title>
    <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Assignment overview</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/img/social-image.png</url>
      <title>Assignment overview</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does it Work and Why Does it Work?</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/01-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/01-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#idea-no-idea&#34;&gt;Idea: No Idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;idea-no-idea&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Idea: No Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically pages that are not required to visit will be greyed out on the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/schedule/&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt; page. While there isn’t an exercise this week, please take this time to go through the first week of material on Data Camp. It is important that you understand the basics and develop some familiarity with R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>80% of Your Time with Data is Dedicated to Wrangling!</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/02-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/02-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#task-assessing-common-descriptives&#34;&gt;Task: Assessing Common Descriptives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;task-assessing-common-descriptives&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Task: Assessing Common Descriptives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package and scroll through the data sets or alternatively click &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fivethirtyeight/data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see the FiveThirtyEight GitHub repository. Locate a response set that is derived from a survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run some basic descriptive statistics on the set. What you explore and/or report on is up to you. What I really want is for you to get comfortable (well as much as possible) with writing syntax. The more you try, the more I can comment on! Please turn in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your R script (.R format) with your name in the upper left-hand corner beside of a hashtag # so it appears as a comment. Please please please make sure to provide comments for clarification and format your script so that it is clear and understandable. An example scripts is included which can be accessed &lt;a href=&#34;https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/exscripts/example_script.R&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You may either right click and download the file to open it or copy and paste the content to your own blank script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want some help with commands, give these sites a try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statmethods.net/stats/descriptives.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick-R by DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcompanion.org/handbook/C_02.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Summary and Analysis of Extension Program Evaluation in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sthda.com/english/wiki/descriptive-statistics-and-graphics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;STHDA - Statistical tools for high-throughput data analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… and if you’re still stuck, ask a peer and then please contact me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a maximum one page 12-point font double spaced description of what (a) the data set was about, (b) you explored and (c) you wish you knew how to do in R to better understand the data set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra credit may be awarded for those who apply statistics beyond descriptives. If you want some fun ideas, run the following and select some of the user-contributed scripts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;vignette(&amp;quot;user_contributed_vignettes&amp;quot;, package = &amp;quot;fivethirtyeight&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truthiness, Damned Truthiness, and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/03-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/03-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#task-exploring-icpsr&#34;&gt;Task: Exploring ICPSR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#note-triangulation&#34;&gt;Note: Triangulation!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;task-exploring-icpsr&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Task: Exploring ICPSR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please use this roadmap to download a data set of your choice to analyze:
1. Go to the data repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ICPSR&lt;/a&gt; out of the University of Michigan.
2. Sign up for an account &lt;strong&gt;with your university email address&lt;/strong&gt; because you will be able to download available data sets given that WVU is a member institution.
3. After logging in fully, go to the &lt;code&gt;FIND DATA&lt;/code&gt; tab and then select &lt;code&gt;FIND DATA&lt;/code&gt; in the drop down (that’s not confusing at all).
4. Search for a data set that both interests you and is measurable by typing in a topic. Ideally you want to find a data set that have responses that are quantified, have a scale, and that scale is consistent across multiple items.
5. After the search has completed, you may notice there are filters on the left hand side. Scroll down to &lt;code&gt;Data Availibility&lt;/code&gt; and select &lt;code&gt;Public Data&lt;/code&gt;. If you do not see this option, then you’ll have to search for some other topic.
6. You can also enable other filters like &lt;code&gt;Data Format&lt;/code&gt; where you can find both &lt;code&gt;Delimited&lt;/code&gt; (aka &lt;code&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; files) and &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; files too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your task is three fold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;describe the data in layman’s terms but not informally. Explain it to me as if you were trying to describe it to a fourth - sixth grade student. A popular indicator is through the a score derived from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://readable.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flesch–Kincaid Reading Grade Level&lt;/a&gt;. This tool has about 50 years of controversy attached to it, which could easily be an entire chapter of a clearance bin book. Please note that you do not need to report if you applied a readability test to your narrative or how you did it. I just wanted to point out an approach that may be useful in giving you an idea if your narrative is in the ballpark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;note-triangulation&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Note: Triangulation!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever side of the coin you may settle on, this is just a perfect example of why using a single measure is simply a bad idea since you run the risk of an entire study or studies being reliant on a single measure whose validity in this case may be in flux. Barring some well known measures, it is recommended that at least three different indicators are used to assess a construct. This three way assessemment strategy is called &lt;em&gt;triangulation&lt;/em&gt;. An well-written and relatively short description of this idea can be accessed through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://assessment.uncc.edu/student-learning-outcomes/resources/triangulation-student-learning-outcomes-assessment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UNC Charlotte Office of Academic Affairs&lt;/a&gt; Regardless, its utility is widespread and so much so that it has been a default measure within &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/get-your-document-s-readability-and-level-statistics-85b4969e-e80a-4777-8dd3-f7fc3c8b3fd2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft Word&lt;/a&gt; for nearly twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run some reliability checks&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of one to three constructs (not items - you group items together to assess a construct). Then decide which single measure most accurately describes the true internal consistency. Defend your choice with a maximum 280 word (aka 1 Tweet’s worth) or less argument. My advice is to first look at both the codebook and measures. Additionally, choose wisely because you’ll be addressing validity, or rather something called &lt;em&gt;threats to validity&lt;/em&gt; next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit the items below as separate pieces using the Submission Portal on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ecampus.wvu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eCampus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;an R script (.R format) with your name in the upper left-hand corner beside of a hashtag # so it appears as a comment. Again please provide comments where it is not obvious what you are doing. Perpetually, an example script is included which can be accessed &lt;a href=&#34;https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/exscripts/example_script.R&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The more directions you include, the better the response! You may either right click and download the file to open it or copy and paste the content to your own blank script.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a maximum one page 12-point font double spaced reflection that includes brief narratives on what&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the data set was about,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was explored,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you wish you knew how to do in R to better understand the data set, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reliability measures were tested, your final decision, and what brought you to that choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a one page data visualization of your choice with a maximum 280 word or less argument defending your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please note that you are not restricted to the ones covered in this week’s Example&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pirates Cause Global Warming</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/04-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/04-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#task-rfps-with-reliability-and-validity&#34;&gt;Task: RFPs with Reliability and Validity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;task-rfps-with-reliability-and-validity&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Task: RFPs with Reliability and Validity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A request for proposal (RFP) is a dispersed document that solicits proposals by an agency, company or organization interested in conducting an evaluation. For example, you can go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://careers.eval.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;American Evaluation Association’s (AEA) Career Center&lt;/a&gt; and simply type &lt;code&gt;rfp&lt;/code&gt; in the Keyword or Job Title box to take a look at current opportunities and their respective requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of proposals are often lucrative but highly competitive.
Since most RFPs are submitted without any opportunities for follow-ups or clarifications, stakeholder or sponsor will pick the one that has the greatest detail, clearly written, and does not promise too little or even too much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final project in this course is derived from a much larger study of what employers look for in an evaluator. The requirements of particular task is a carbon copy of findings related to RFPs specifically where documents were analyzed from a systematic sample of two years of RFPs posted on the website listed above and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eval.org/p/cm/ld/fid=113&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AEA’s Jobs/RFPs&lt;/a&gt; site as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you certainly won’t be writing an entire RFP, the criteria will give you practice in addressing an instrumentation and measurement section. Now on to the fun part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First either choose to use an existing instrument or develop one yourself. Now please submit a proposal outlining&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed test items
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a description of a current or developing instrument you wish to study including what the entire piece is intended to assess including details related to items or groups of items that may be or are measuring differing constructs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an explanation of (a) how the items were decided upon and (b) how the number of items was determined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed Reliability Assessment
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An explanation of how the administration (and/or scoring) of the test will permit you to determine its reliability. Please be specific about which reliability coefficient you are proposing and use the appropriate terminology (e.g., test-retest reliability will be computed by correlating scores obtained from administering the test to a randomly selected group of program participants and re-administering the test to the same group on six months later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed Validity Assessment
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification and description of the group for which you want the test to be valid for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptions of at least one approach for computing the content validity, concurrent validity and predictive validity of your test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for this RFP is Thursday, August 6 by 11:59PM. The structure and page length is typical for an average sized multi year RFP that a single evaluator would be able conduct ion an individual basis. The proposal should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be three to five pages double spaced with both front and back used with 12 point Times New Roman font;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include both () your name and a working title in the header such that it repeats on every page and (b) page numbers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a full working or current draft of the proposed instrument attached in an appendix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;follow all APA 7th Edition guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have support (e.g. references of previous studies) where &lt;em&gt;an assertion is made&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be clearly and concisely written, You simply do not have enough space to get wordy, so read and critique your proposal over and over until you are simply sick of it. If you get to the point where all criteria are met but you are at the “to hell with this and him” stage, then the proposal is probably in a good state to be submitted.
:::&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors! FACTORS! They’re Everywhere! Your Firearms Are Useless Against Them!</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/05-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/05-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#idea-exploratory-factor-analysis-efa&#34;&gt;Idea: Exploratory Factor Analysis (EFA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#locating-data&#34;&gt;Locating Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-turn-in&#34;&gt;What to Turn in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;idea-exploratory-factor-analysis-efa&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Idea: Exploratory Factor Analysis (EFA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;locating-data&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Locating Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll want to first locate a raw data set with (a) survey responses using the same column and row formatting structure as the set that was used in the example AND (b) a code book that has clearly defined the variables (columns). Make sure you keep an accurate record of what data set was used and where you got it from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the same list of possible resources from last week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.opendata.aws/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AWS public datasets&lt;/a&gt; - This stands for Amazon Web Service and yes its that Amazon. Believe it or not, Amazon is one of the largest providers of APIs (acronym for &lt;em&gt;application programming interface&lt;/em&gt; which is a fancy way to say a service where computer programs can talk to each other), data analytics (fancy of way of saying that a computer is being used for stats), data processing (fancy way of say how efficient data can be analyzed, rearranged, whatever), and storage cloud computing (fancy way of saying securing, sharing and storing data and sharing it). To this end, a lot and I mean a lot of data sets are publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.baidu.com/broad/introduction?dataset=dureader&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Baidu Research&lt;/a&gt; - Baidu provides a wide range of data sets at no cost for research and personal uses. They provide data from the various business units like automated car testing, medical, video highlight. While it is unlikely you’ll locate a survey response set, this is a good thing to note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data.gov&lt;/a&gt; - In the United States, all publicly funded data sets are available barring those that may pose a security threat (but you can even get those eventually using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foia.gov/data.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Freedom of Information Act&lt;/a&gt;). Other bodies freely share their data as well such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/en/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;. There are plenty of other organizations that share their data too. For example, whatever your opinion is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.worldbank.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;World Bank&lt;/a&gt;or even if you don’t have one, even they shares their data since it is publicly funded as well!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data.world&lt;/a&gt; - One of the best publicly available repos out there. Some of the sets even come with full R scripts! Other software scripts like Excel, Python, SPSS, SAS, etc are available as well. This is strictly user driven so availability is contingent on who shares what and how.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github - Not only are public data sets plentiful on Github, but people have also taken the time to compile a list for the rest of us. Here are a few popular ones (I promise not every repo is named awesome on Github):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Awesome Public Datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/viisar/awesome-datasets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Awesome Data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://toolbox.google.com/datasetsearch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Dataset Search&lt;/a&gt; - Much like nearly every other Google service (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;), Goggle Datasets doesn’t actually house anything, rather it is a means for you to get to data, aka a portal what a fantastic name), without having to search all over the web. It is fairly new and their database grows every second - actually its faster than that but as humans we have trouble compartmentalizing any unit of time smaller than a second. Now if you’ve heard the term &lt;em&gt;indexing&lt;/em&gt;, that is not this. The best analogy I can think of is creating a grocery shopping list as needed through the week (aka adding to the data base) and then reordering and grouping food items that are closest in proximity to each other so that you can get out of the store as quick and efficiently as possible&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; - Described as an AirBnB for data scientists, this site has a ton of public and sometimes private data that has been cleared for public consumption. More than that, it is an absolute playpen if you like exploring data. If you go headfirst into a data set and cannot and I mean cannot cognitively picture an end goal or what the data will tell you until something is done with it, this is the place for you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-to-turn-in&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Turn in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have located a data set, do the data scientist thing and please follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up the codebook and locate multiple columns:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one that has a unique identifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one quantiative column of your choice that is not filled with demographical information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the same steps outlined in the example piece to conduct your own exploratory factor analysis (EFA).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Answer the following questions on a word document. As usual, please put your name in the upper left hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: lower-alpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the official name of the data set you chose?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What repository did you get it from (e.g. data.world, Kaggle, etc)? If you did not get it from a place where data is housed, please copy and paste the web address. Please do not copy and paste any additional nonsense that say search engines put on a web address. For example, if you’ve ever copied and pasted a website after using Google, you may notice that the address is obnoxiously long. I don’t want that. If you are having trouble, contact me and I’ll help you through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you determine the number of factors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the factors likely representative of? &lt;em&gt;hint: look at the loadings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the results into a single paragraph narrative. Try to be specific and concise. There is a very narrow way to interpret the results of a factor analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit your script, a copy of the data set and responses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ecampus.wvu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eCampus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try doing this if you don’t like shopping!&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From a Certain Poimt of View... A Certain Point of View?</title>
      <link>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/06-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://edp611.theoreticalphysed.com/assignment/06-exercise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#idea-principle-component-analysis-pca&#34;&gt;Idea: Principle Component Analysis (PCA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#locating-data&#34;&gt;Locating Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-turn-in&#34;&gt;What to Turn in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;idea-principle-component-analysis-pca&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Idea: Principle Component Analysis (PCA)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;locating-data&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Locating Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll want to first locate a raw data set with (a) survey responses using the same column and row formatting structure as the set that was used in the example AND (b) a code book that has clearly defined the variables (columns). Make sure you keep an accurate record of what data set was used and where you got it from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where can you find data you ask? Oh you didn’t. Well its too late now so here are some suggestions. These are given in alphabetical order without any preferential ranking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.opendata.aws/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AWS public datasets&lt;/a&gt; - This stands for Amazon Web Service and yes its that Amazon. Believe it or not, Amazon is one of the largest providers of APIs (acronym for &lt;em&gt;application programming interface&lt;/em&gt; which is a fancy way to say a service where computer programs can talk to each other), data analytics (fancy of way of saying that a computer is being used for stats), data processing (fancy way of say how efficient data can be analyzed, rearranged, whatever), and storage cloud computing (fancy way of saying securing, sharing and storing data and sharing it). To this end, a lot and I mean a lot of data sets are publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.baidu.com/broad/introduction?dataset=dureader&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Baidu Research&lt;/a&gt; - Baidu provides a wide range of data sets at no cost for research and personal uses. They provide data from the various business units like automated car testing, medical, video highlight. While it is unlikely you’ll locate a survey response set, this is a good thing to note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.data.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data.gov&lt;/a&gt; - In the United States, all publicly funded data sets are available barring those that may pose a security threat (but you can even get those eventually using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foia.gov/data.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Freedom of Information Act&lt;/a&gt;). Other bodies freely share their data as well such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/en/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;. There are plenty of other organizations that share their data too. For example, whatever your opinion is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.worldbank.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;World Bank&lt;/a&gt;or even if you don’t have one, even they shares their data since it is publicly funded as well!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.world/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data.world&lt;/a&gt; - One of the best publicly available repos out there. Some of the sets even come with full R scripts! Other software scripts like Excel, Python, SPSS, SAS, etc are available as well. This is strictly user driven so availability is contingent on who shares what and how.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github - Not only are public data sets plentiful on Github, but people have also taken the time to compile a list for the rest of us. Here are a few popular ones (I promise not every repo is named awesome on Github):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awesomedata/awesome-public-datasets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Awesome Public Datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/viisar/awesome-datasets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Awesome Data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://toolbox.google.com/datasetsearch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Dataset Search&lt;/a&gt; - Much like nearly every other Google service (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;), Goggle Datasets doesn’t actually house anything, rather it is a means for you to get to data, aka a portal what a fantastic name), without having to search all over the web. It is fairly new and their database grows every second - actually its faster than that but as humans we have trouble compartmentalizing any unit of time smaller than a second. Now if you’ve heard the term &lt;em&gt;indexing&lt;/em&gt;, that is not this. The best analogy I can think of is creating a grocery shopping list as needed through the week (aka adding to the data base) and then reordering and grouping food items that are closest in proximity to each other so that you can get out of the store as quick and efficiently as possible&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; - Described as an AirBnB for data scientists, this site has a ton of public and sometimes private data that has been cleared for public consumption. More than that, it is an absolute playpen if you like exploring data. If you go headfirst into a data set and cannot and I mean cannot cognitively picture an end goal or what the data will tell you until something is done with it, this is the place for you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-to-turn-in&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to Turn in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have located a data set, do the data scientist thing and please follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up the codebook and locate multiple columns:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one that has a unique identifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiple with quantiative data that have relationships or are being used to assess the same measure&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the same steps outlined in the example piece to conduct your own principal component analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Answer the following questions on a word document. As usual, please put your name in the upper left hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: lower-alpha&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the official name of the data set you chose?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What repository did you get it from (e.g. data.world, Kaggle, etc)? If you did not get it from a place where data is housed, please copy and paste the web address. Please do not copy and paste any additional nonsense that say search engines put on a web address. For example, if you’ve ever copied and pasted a website after using Google, you may notice that the address is obnoxiously long. I don’t want that. If you are having trouble, contact me and I’ll help you through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you determine the number of components?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do the components tell you? &lt;em&gt;hint: look at the loadings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the results into a single paragraph narrative. Try to be specific and concise. There is a very narrow way to interpret the results of a PCA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit your script, a copy of the data set and responses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ecampus.wvu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eCampus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try doing this if you don’t like shopping!&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None should be filled with demographical information.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
